I feel like you're driving me to court martial. This is crazy
What did I do? I feel like you're gonna pull over and snuff me
What, you're not allowed to talk? Hey, Forest...
- We can talk, sir. - Oh, I see. So it's personal?
No, you intimidate them
Dear God, you're a woman! I honestly, I couldn't have called that
I mean, I would apologize, but isn't that what we're going for here?
I thought of you as a soldier first. - I'm an airman
Well you have actually excellent bone structure there. I'm kinda...
having a hard time not looking at you now. Is that weird?
C'mon, it's OK, laugh. Hey!
- Sir, I have a question to ask. - Yes, please
It is true you went 12-for-12 with last year's Maxim cover models?
That is an excellent question
Yes and no. March and I had a scheduling conflict
but fortunately the Christmas cover was twins. Anything else?
You're kidding me with a hand up, right?
Is it cool if I take a picture with you?
Yes, it's very cool
I don't wanna see this on your MySpace page
Please, no gang signs
No, throw it up, I'm kidding
Yeah, peace! I love peace. I'd be outta job with peace
C'mon! Just click it, don't change the settings, just click it
What's going on?
Jimmy, stay with Stark!
Lie down!
Son of a bitch!
- Wait, wait, give me a gun! - Stay here!
Tony Stark
Visionary. Genius. American patriot
Even from an early age
the son of legendary weapons developer Howard Stark
quickly stole the spotlight with his brilliant and unique mind
At age four, he built his first circuit board
At age six, his first engine
And at seventeen, he graduated Summa Cum Laude from MIT
Then, the passing of a titan
Howard Stark's life long friend and ally Obadiah Stane
steps in to help fill the gap left by the legendary founder
Until at age 21, the prodigal son returns
and is anointed the new CEO of Stark Industries
With the keys to the kingdom, Tony ushers in a new era
for his father's legacy, creating smarter weapons
advanced robotics, satellite targeting
Today, Tony Stark has changed the face of the weapons industry
by ensuring freedom
and protecting America and her interests around the globe
As liaison to Stark Industries
I've had the unique privilege of serving with a real patriot
He is my friend and he is my great mentor
Ladies and gentlemen, it is my honor
to present this year's Apogee Award to Mr. Tony Stark!
Tony?
Thank you, Colonel
This is beautiful. Thank you
Thank you all very much. This is wonderful
Well, I'm not Tony Stark
But if I were Tony...
...I would tell you how honored I feel
and what a joy it is to receive this very prestigious award
Tony, you know, the best thing about Tony...
...is also the worst thing - he's always working
C'mon!
We should just stay till the morning
- You are unbelievable! - Oh, no. They roped you into this?
Nobody roped me into anything. But they told me...
that if I presented you with an award, you'd be deeply honored
Of course I'd be deeply honored. And it's you!
That's great. So when do we do it? One more round. - There you go
There it is. That was easy. I'm so sorry. - Yeah, it's OK
Wow, would you look at that? That's... that's something else
I don't have any of those swooping around. All right, ride!
Give me a hand, will you? OK, you too
I don't blow on man's hands
There it is! It's the Lieutenant Colonel Rhodes' roll, and...
That's what happens
Worse things have happened, I think we're gonna be fine
Color me up, will you? - This is where I exit
- Tomorrow don't be late. - Yeah, you can count on it
- I'm serious. - I know, I know
Render unto Caesar that which is Caesar's. There you go
Mr. Stark! Excuse me! Mr. Stark!
Christine Everheart, Vanity Fair magazine
Can I ask you a couple of questions? - She's cute
- She's alright? Hi. - Hi
Yeah. Okay, go
You've been called the Da Vinci of our time. What do you say to that?
Absolutely ridiculous. I don't paint
And what do you say to your other nickname, the Merchant of Death?
That's not bad. Let me guess... Berkeley?
Brown, actually
Well, Ms. Brown
It's an imperfect world, but it's the only one we've got
I guarantee you the day weapons are no longer needed to keep the peace
we'll start making bricks and beams for baby hospitals
Rehearse that much?
Every night in front of the mirror before bedtime
- I can see that. - I'd like to show you firsthand
All I want is the serious answer
Okay, here is serious. My old man had a philosophy:
"Peace means having a bigger stick than the other guy. "
That's a great line, coming from a guy selling the sticks
My father helped defeat Nazis. He worked on the Manhattan Project
A lot of people, including your professors at Brown
would call that being a hero
And a lot of people would also call that war-profiteering
Tell me, do you plan to report
on the millions we've saved by advancing medical technology?
Or kept from starvation with our intelli-crops?
All those breakthroughs: military funding, honey
Wow, did you ever lose an hour of sleep your whole life?
I'd be prepared to lose a few with you
Good morning. It's 7 a. m
The weather in Malibu is 72 degrees with scattered clouds
The surf conditions are fair with waist to shoulder highlines
high tide will be at 10:52 a. m
Tony? Hey, Tony!
You are not authorized to access this area. - Jesus!
That's Jarvis, he runs the house
I've got your clothes here, they've been dry cleaned and pressed
And there's a car waiting for you outside
that will take you anywhere you'd like to go
You must be the famous Pepper Potts. - Indeed I am
After all these years, Tony still has you picking up the dry cleaning?
I do anything and everything that Mr. Stark requires
Including occasionally taking out the trash. Would that be all?
Give me the exploded view
The compression in cylinder 3 appears to be low
Note that
- I'll try again later... - Please don't turn down my music
I'll keep you posted
You are supposed to be half way around the world right now
- How did she take it? - Like a champ
Might've tried to hustle me out of here
Your flight was scheduled to leave an hour and a half ago
That's funny... I thought with it being my plane and all
that it would just wait for me to get there
I need to speak to you about couple of things before I get you outta the door
I mean, doesn't it kind of defeat the purpose of having your own plane
if it departs before you arrive?
Larry called, he's got another buyer for the Jackson Pollock
in the wings, do you want it, yes or no?
Is it a good representation of his Spring Period?
No the "Springs" is actually the neighborhood in East Hampton
where he lived and worked, not "spring" like the season
I think it's a fair example...
I think it's incredibly overpriced
I need it. Buy it, store it
Okay... the MIT commencement speech
Is in June... please, don't harangue me about that stuff
Well, they are haranguing me, so I'm gonna say yes...
I need you to sign this before you get on the plane
What are you trying to get rid of me for? What, you got plans?
- As a matter of fact, I do. - I don't like it when you have plans
I'm allowed to have plans on my birthday
It's your birthday. - Yes. - I knew that. Already?
Yeah, isn't that strange, it's the same day as last year
Well, get yourself something nice from me. - I already did
- And? - Oh, it was very nice
Very tasteful. Thank you, Mr. Stark
You're welcome, Ms. Potts
You're good! I thought I've lost you back there
You did, sir
I took it across Mojave. - Ah, I gotcha, I gotcha
What's wrong with you? - What?
Three hours! - I got caught doing a piece for Vanity Fair
Three hours. For three hours, you got me standing here
I'm waiting on you now. Lets go. C'mon
Wheels up! Rock and roll!
What're you reading? - Nothing
C'mon, sourpatch, don't be mad
I told you I'm not mad, I'm indifferent, okay?
- I said I was sorry. - Good morning, Mr. Stark
- No need to apologize. - I told him I was sorry but he...
I'm just indifferent right now
You don't respect yourself, so I know you don't respect me
- I respect you. - I'm just your babysitter
and so, when you need your diaper changed, thank you...
let me know and I'll get you a bottle, okay?
Hey, heat up the sake, will you? Thanks for reminding me
I'm not talking... we're not drinking, we're working right now
And you are constitutionally incapable of being responsible
It would be irresponsible not to drink
I'm just talking about the night cup. - Hot sake?
- Yes, two please. - No, just...
I'm not drinking, I don't want any
That's what I'm talking about. When I get up in the morning
and I'm putting on my uniform, you know what I recognize?
I see in that mirror that every person that's got this uniform
will get my back! - Here we go again. I'm not like you
No, you don't have to be like me. But you're more than... yes you are
Will you excuse me, I'm a little bit distracted here
No, you can't be distracted right now. Listen to me!
BAGRAM AIR BASE, AFGHANISTAN
General
Welcome, Mr. Stark
We look forward to your weapons presentation
Is it better to be feared or respected?
And I say, is it too much to ask for both?
With that in mind, I humbly present the crown jewel
of Stark Industries freedom line. It's the first missile system
to incorporate our proprietary repulsor technology
They say the best weapon is one you never have to fire
I respectfully disagree
I prefer the weapon you only have to fire once
That's how dad did it, that's how America does it...
and it's worked out pretty well so far
Find an excuse to let one of these off the chain
and I personally guarantee you
the bad guys won't even want to come out of their caves
For your consideration, the Jericho
We throw one of these in with every purchase of 500 million or more
To peace!
- Tony. - Obie, what are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep till I found out how it went. How did it go?
Went great, looks like it's gonna be an early Christmas
Hey, way to go, my boy. I'll see you tomorrow, yeah?
Why aren't you wearing those pyjamas I got you?
Good night, Tony
Hey Tony!
I'm sorry, this is the fun-vee. The hum-drum-vee is back there
- Nice job. - See you back at base
I wouldn't do that if I were you
What the hell did you do to me?
What I did?
What I did is to save your life
I removed all the shrapnel I could, but there's a lot left
and it's headed into your atrial septum
Here, wanna see?
I have a souvenir. Take a look
I've seen many wounds like that in my village
We call them the walking dead
Because in takes about a week for the balls to reach the vital organs
- What is this? - That is an electromagnet
Hooked up to a car battery
And it's keeping the shrapnel from entering your heart
That's right. Smile!
We met once, you know
At the technical conference in Bern
- Don't remember. - No, you wouldn't
If I had been that drunk, I wouldn't have been able to stand
much less give a lecture on integrated circuits
Where are we?
Come on, stand up. Stand up
Do as I do
C'mon, put your hands up
Those are my guns. How did they get my guns?
Do you understand me? Do as I do
He says: "Welcome Tony Stark
the most famous mass murderer in the history of America. "
He is honored
He wants you to build a missile
The Jericho missile that you demonstrated
This one
I refuse
Tony!
He wants to know what you think
I think he got a lot of my weapons
He says they have everything you need to build a Jericho missile
He wants you to make the list of materials
He says for you to start working immediately
and when you're done, he will set you free
No, I won't
No, he won't
I'm sure they're looking for you, Stark
But they will never find you in these mountains
Look...
What you just saw... that is your legacy, Stark
Your life's work in the hands of those murderers
Is that how you want to go out?
Is this the last act of defiance of the great Tony Stark?
Or are you going to do something about it?
Why should I do anything? They're gonna kill me, you...
Either way, if they don't, I'll probably be dead in a week
Well then... this is a very important week for you, isn't it?
If this is gonna be my workstation
I want it well lit, I want all of these tools
Welding gear, I don't care if it's acetylene or propane
I need a soldering station, I need helmets
I need goggles, I would like a smelting cup
I need two sets of precision tools
How many languages do you speak?
A lot. But apparently not enough for this place
They speak Arabic, Urdu, Dari, Pashto
Mongolian, Farsi, Russian
Who are these people?
They are your loyal customers, sir
They call themselves The Ten Rings
You know, we might be more productive
if you include me in the planning process? - Aha
Okay. We don't need this
What is that?
That's palladium, 0.15 grams. We need at least 1.6
so why don't you go break down the other eleven
What are they doing?
Working
Careful. Careful, we only get one shot at this
Relax, I've steady hands
Why do you think you're still alive, huh?
What do I call you?
- My name is Yinsen. - Yinsen... nice to meet you
Nice to meet you too
Wow, that doesn't look like a Jericho missile
That's because it is a miniaturized Arc reactor
We got a big one powering my factory at home
It should keep the shrapnel out of my heart
But what could it generate?
If my math is right, and it always is...
three gigajoules per second
That could run your heart for the 50 lifetimes. - Yeah
Or something big for 50 minutes
This is our ticket outta here. - What is it?
'Flying the mountain' look
Impressive
Shesh Besh
Good roll. Good roll
You still didn't tell me where you're from
I'm from a small town called Gulmira
It's actually a nice place
- You got a family? - Yes
And I will see them when I leave here
And you, Stark?
Nothing
No
So you're a man who has everything... and nothing
Doesn't look anything like the photo
Maybe he modified it
- The tail doesn't seem right. - Well, too bad
Relax
The bow and arrow once was the pinnacle of weapons technology
It allowed the great Genghis Khan
to rule from the Pacific to the Ukraine
An empire twice the size of Alexander the Great
And four times the size of the Roman empire
But today
whoever holds the latest Stark weapons
rules these lands
And soon...
...it will be my turn
Why did you fail me?
We're working on it. Diligently
I spared your life
Is this how you repay me?
It's very complex
We're trying hard
On your knees
You think I'm an idiot?
Tell me the truth
We are working hard
Open your mouth
- What does he want? - You think I'm a fool?
What is going on?
Tell me the truth
We are working on Jericho
What do you want, a delivery date?
I need him
He's a good assistant
You have till tomorrow...
...to assemble my missile
- Okay? - Yes
Can you move?
Say it again
41 steps straight ahead
then 16 steps, left from the door, four to the right
33 steps, turn right
Where is Stark?
He was here a moment ago
Go find him!
Yinsen!
Yinsen! Stark!
Say something
He is speaking Hungarian, I don't...
- Speak Hungarian. - Okay...
What do you know?
- How did that work? - Oh my goodness
- It worked all right. - What do I do?
- Let me finish this. - Finish last powering sequence
Okay
Now! Tell me, tell me!
F 11. Tell me when you see a progress bar
It should be up right now
Talk to me, tell me when you see it. - I have it
- Press Ctrl + I. - Got it
'Enter'. I, 'Enter'. Come over here and button me up
They are coming!
Doesn't need to look pretty, just get it done
They are coming
Make sure that checkpoints are clear before you follow me out, OK?
We need more time
Okay
I'm gonna go buy you some time
Stick to the plan!
Yinsen!
- Yinsen! - Watch out!
Stark
Come on. We gotta go
Move with me. C'mon, we got a plan, we need to stick to it
This was always the plan, Stark
Come on, you're going to go see your family again
My family is dead
I'm going to see them now, Stark
It's okay. It's okay
I want this. I want this
Thank you for saving me
Don't waste it. Don't waste your life
My turn
Not bad
How was the fun-vee?
Next time you ride with me, okay?
Watch it coming up here
Are you kidding me with this? Get rid of them
Your eyes are red
Few tears for your long lost boss?
Tears of joy. I hate job hunting
Yeah, vacation's over
Where to, sir?
Take us to the hospital, please. - No. - No? Tony...
- You have to go to the hospital. - I don't have to do anything
I was in captivity for three months. There are two things I want to do
I want an American cheeseburger...
...and the other one... - That's not going to happen
It's not what you think. I want you to call for a press conference now
Call for a press conference? What on earth for?
Yeah, Hogan, drive. Cheeseburger first
Look at this!
Tony!
I thought you'll be in a hospital
Look at you!
Oh, burger, you had to have a burger
Did you get me one of those?
There was only one left, I needed it
Hey, look who's here!
- Ms. Potts? - Yes
May I speak with you for a moment?
I'm not part of the press conference, but it's about to begin right now
I am not a reporter. I'm agent Phil Coulson
with the Strategic Homeland Intervention
Enforcement and Logistics Division
- That's quite a mouthful. - I know. We're working on it
We've been approached already by the DOD, FBI, CIA...
We are a separate division. With a more specific focus
We need to debrief Mr. Stark about the circumstances of his escape
- I'll put something in a book, shell I? - Thank you
Hey, would it be alright if everyone sat down?
Will you sit down? That way you can see me, and I can...
A little less formal...
What's up with the lovin'?
Don't look at me, I don't know what he's up to
- Good to see you. - Good to see you
I never got to say goodbye to dad
I never got to say goodbye to my father
There's questions that I would've asked him
I would've asked him how he felt about what his company did...
...if he was conflicted, if he ever had doubts
Or maybe he was every inch of a man we all remember from the newsreels
I saw young Americans killed...
...by the very weapons I created to defend them and protect them
And I saw that I had become part of a system
that is comfortable with zero-accountability
What happened over there?
I had my eyes opened
I came to realize that I have more to offer
this world than just making things that blow up
And that is why, effective immediately, I'm shutting down
the weapons manufacturing division of Stark International...
...untill such a time, as I can decide
what the future of this company will be
what direction it should take, the one I'm comfortable with
and is consistent with the highest good of this country and the world
What we should take away from this...
...is that Tony's back!
And he's healthier than ever
We are gonna have a little internal discussion
and we'll get back to you with a follow-up
- Where is he? - He's inside
That... that went well
Did I just paint a target on the back of my head?
Your head? What about my head?
What do you think the over-under on a stock drop is gonna be?
- Optimistically? 40 Points? - At minimum
Tony, we're a weapons manufacturer
Obie, I just... I don't want the body count to be up...
That's what we do. We're iron mongers, we make weapons
My name is on facade of the building
What we do keeps the world from falling into chaos
Not based on what I saw
We're not doing a good enough job
We can do better, we're gonna do something else
Oh, like what? You want us to make baby bottles?
I think we should take another look into Arc Reactor technology
Oh, come on. The Arc Reactor, that's a publicity stunt!
Tony, c'mon! We built that thing to shut the hippies up!
- It works. - Yeah, as a science project
The Arc was never cost-effective. We knew that before we built it
Arc Reactor technology, that's a dead end, right?
- Maybe. - Am I right?
We haven't had a breakthrough in that, in what... 30 years
That's what they say
Could you have a lousier poker face?
Just tell me, who told you? - Never mind who told me
- Show me. - Rhodey or Pepper
- I wanna see it. - Okay, Rhodey
It works
Listen to me, Tony
We are a team, do you understand?
There's nothing we can't do if we stick together
like your father and I
I'm sorry I didn't give you a heads up, okay? But if I had...
Tony, no more of this 'ready - fire - aim' business
- Do you understand me? - That was dad's line
You gotta let me handle this
We're gonna have to play whole different kind of ball now
We're gonna have to take a lot of heat
I want you to promise me that you're gonna lay low
Stark Industries. I've got one recommendation. Ready, ready?
Sell, sell, sell!
Abandon ship!
Does the 'Hindenburg' ring any bells?
Let me show you the new Stark Industries business plan!
Look, that's a weapons company that doesn't make weapons!
Pepper! How big are your hands?
- What? - How big are your hands?
- I don't understand why... - Get down here. I need you
Hey!
Let's see them. Show me your hands
Let's see them
Oh, wow, they are small. Very petite, indeed
I just need your help for a sec
Oh my God, is that the thing that's keeping you alive?
It was, it is now an antique
This is what will be keeping me alive for the foreseeable future
I was swapping it up for an upgraded unit
and I just ran into a little... speed bump
Speed bump? What's happening?
It's nothing, it's just a little snag
There's an exposed wire under this device
and is contacting a socket wall
and is causing a little bit of a short circuit
What do you want me to do?
Put that on the table over there. That is irrelevant
I just want you to reach in...
and you're just gonna gently lift the wire out
Is it safe?
Yeah, it should be fine. It's just like an operation
you just don't let it touch the socket wall
- What's Operation? - It's just a game, never mind
- Just gently lift the wire. - Okay. - Okay? Great
You know, I don't think that I am qualified to do this
No, no, you're fine. You're the most capable
qualified and trustworthy person I've ever met
You're gonna do great
Is it too much of a problem to ask? Cause I really need your help here
- Oh, there's pus! - It's not pus
It's a plasmic discharge, it's from the device, not from my body
- It smells! - Yeah, it does
The copper wire
The copper wire, you got it? - I got it
Now don't let it touch...
...the sides, that's what I was trying to tell you before
Okay, now make sure that when you pull it out
you don't pull out the magnet and the end of it. That was it...
...that you just pulled out. - Oh God. OK, what do I do?
- Don't put it back in! - What's wrong?
Nothing, I'm just going into cardiac arrest cause you yanked out...
- What? I thought you said this was safe! - We gotta hurry
Take this, you gotta switch, real quick. - Okay, okay
Tony, it's gonna be okay. I'm gonna make this okay
You gotta touch that to base plate
And make sure you...
Was that so hard?
That was fun, right? I got it, I got it
Nice
- Are you okay? - Yeah, I feel great
Are you okay?
Don't ever, ever...
...ever ask me to do anything like that ever again
I don't have anyone but you
Are we ready?
What do you want me to do with this?
That? Destroy it. Incinerate it
You don't wanna keep it?
Pepper, I've been called many things
Nostalgic is not one of them
- Would that be all, Mr. Stark? - That would be all, Ms. Potts
Hey butterfingers, come here
What's all this stuff doing on top of my desk?
That's my phone, that's a picture of me and my dad...
Right there. In garbage. All that stuff
The future of air combat
Is it manned or unmanned?
I tell you, in my experience, no unmanned aerial vehicle
will ever trump a pilot's instinct
his insight - that ability to look into a situation
beyond the obvious and discern its outcome
Or pilot's judgement
Colonel, it's... why not a pilot without a plane?
Look who fell outta the sky! Mr. Tony Stark
Speaking about manned or unmanned
you gotta get him to tell you about the time he guessed wrong
It's spring break, just remember that
Spring break 1987, that lovely lady, what was his name?
Was it Ivan?
Don't do that, they'll believe it. Don't do that
Give us a couple of minutes, you guys
- I'm surprised. - Why?
I swear I didn't expect to see you walking around so soon
I'm doing a little better than walking
- Really? - Yeah
Rhodey, I'm working on something big
I came to talk to you. I want you to be part of it
You're about to make a whole lotta people around here real happy
cause that little stunt at the press conference, that was juicy
This is not for the military. I'm not... it's different
What, are you humanitarian now or something?
I need you to listen to me
No, what you need is time to get your mind right
I'm serious
It was nice seeing you, Tony
Thanks
- Jarvis, are you up? - For you sir, always
I'd like to open a new project file, index as: Mark 2
Shell I store this on the Stark Industries' central database?
I don't know who to trust right now. Till further notice
why don't we just keep everything on my private server
Working on a secret project, are we, sir?
I don't want this winding up in the wrong hands
Maybe in mine it could actually do some good
Next
Up
Not the boot, Dummy, right here. You got me?
Stay put. Nice
And you, you're no better at it at all. Lift... I got it
Okay, I'm sorry, am I in your way?
Up
That's great, don't even move
You... are a tragedy
Okay, lets do this right
Start mark, half meter back of the center
Dummy, look for light. Stand back for fire safety
You, roll it
Activate hand controls
We are gonna start up nice and easy
raising 10% thrust capacity to achieve lift
And 3, 2, 1
Up two? Alright, step back
I've been buzzing you. Did you hear the intercom?
Yeah, everything's... what?
- Obadiah's upstairs. - Great, I'll be right up
I thought you said you were done making weapons?
It isn't. This is a flight stabilizer
It's completely harmless
I didn't expect that
How'd it go?
Oh, went that bad huh?
Just because I brought pizza back from New York
doesn't mean it went bad. - Sure doesn't. Oh, boy
It would've gone better if you were there
You told me to lay low and that's what I've been doing
I lay low and you take care of all the...
Hey, c'mon. In public, the press...
This was a Board of Directors meeting
This was a Board of Directors meeting?
The Board is claiming a Post Traumatic Stress
They are filing an injunction. - A what?
They wanna lock you out
Why, cause the stocks dip 40 points? We knew this was gonna happen
- 56 and a half. - It doesn't matter
We own a controlling interest in the company
Tony, the Board has rights too
They are making the case that you and your new direction
isn't in a company's best interest
I'm being responsible. That's a new direction
For me... for the company
I mean, me on the company's behalf being responsible for the way that...
- Oh, this is great! - Oh c'mon, wait! Tony, Tony!
- I'll be in the shop. - Hey, hey, Tony, listen
I'm trying to turn this thing around
but you gotta give me something. Something to pitch them
Let me have the engineers analyze that, you know
draw some specs. - No
No. Absolutely not. This one stays with me
That's it Obie. Forget it
Alright, well this stays with me then
Go on, here, you can have a piece. Take two. - Thank you
Do you mind if I come down there to see what you're doing?
Good night, Obie
Day 11, Test 37, Configuration 2.0
For lack of a better option, Dummy is still on fire safety
If you douse me again, and I'm not on fire
I'm donating you to a city college. Alright, nice and easy
Seriously, just gonna start off with 1% thrust capacity
And 3, 2, 1
Please don't follow me around with it either cause I feel
like I'm going to catch on fire spontaneously. Just stand down
If something happens, then come in
Again, lets bring it up to 2.5%. 3, 2, 1...
Okay, this is where I don't want to be
Not the car, not the car
It could be worse. We are fine
Okay, we are getting there
Yeah. I can fly
- Jarvis, are you there? - At your service, sir
Engage head up display. Check
Import all preferences from home interface
Will do, sir
Alright, what do you say?
I have indeed been uploaded, sir. We're online and ready
Start the virtual walkaround
Importing preferences and calibrating virtual environment
- Do a check on control surfaces. - As you wish
Test complete. Preparing to power down and begin diagnostics
Ah, yes... tell you what. Do a weather and ATC check
Start listening the ground control
Sir, there are still terabytes of calculations needed
before an actual flight. - Jarvis...
Sometimes you gotta run before you can walk
Ready? And 3, 2, 1
It feels like a dream
Alright, lets see what this thing can do
What's the SR-71's record?
The altitude record for fixed-wing flight is 85.000 feet, sir
Records are made to be broken. C'mon!
Sir, there is a potentially fatal build-up of ice occurring
Keep going!
Higher!
We're iced up, Jarvis! Deploy flaps
Jarvis?
C'mon, we gotta break the ice!
Cut power
Note: main transducer feels sluggish at plus 40 altitude
The whole pressurization is problematic
I'm thinking 'icy' is a probable factor
A very astute observation, sir. Perhaps if you intend to visit
other planets, we should improve the exo systems
Connect to the Cisco, have it reconfigure the shell metals
Use the gold-titanium alloy from the Seraphim tactical satellite
That should ensure the fuselage integrity
while maintaining power -to-weight ratio. Got it?
Yes. Shall I render using proposed specifications?
Thrill me
Tonight's red hot, red carpeted,
right here at the Disney Concert Hall,
where Tony Stark's third annual benefit for
the Firefighters Family Fund has become the place to be...
Jarvis, did we get an invite from them?
I have no record of the invitation, sir
...haven't been seen in public
since his bizarre and highly controversial press conference.
Some claim he's suffering from PTS and has been
bed ridden for weeks. Whatever the case may be,
no one expects an appearance from him tonight.
The render is complete
Little ostentatious, don't you think?
What was I thinking? You're usually so discrete
Tell you what... throw a little hot rot red in there
Yes, that shall help you keep a low profile
The render is complete
Yeah, I like it. Fabricate it and paint it
Commencing an automated assembly
Estimated completion time is five hours
Don't wait up for me, honey
The weapons manufacturing is...
only a one small part of what Stark Industries is all about...
- Hey Tony, remember me? - I sure don't
You look great, Hef
What's the world coming to when a guy's gotta crash his own party?
Look at you!
- Hey, what a surprise! - I'll see you inside
Listen, take it slow, alright?
I got the Board where I really want them
You got it. Just cabin fever, I'll just be a minute
Give me a Scotch, I'm starving
- Mr. Stark? - Yeah?
- Agent Coulson. - Oh yeah, the guy from the...
Strategic Homeland Intervention
Enforcement and Logistics Division
God, you got... you need a new name for that
Yeah, I hear that a lot
Listen, I know this must be a trying time for you
but we need to debrief you
There's still a lot of unanswered questions
and time can be a factor with these things
Lets just put something on the books
How about the 24th, at 7 p. m. at Stark Industries?
Tell you what... you got it. You're absolutely right
Well... I'm gonna go to my assistant and we'll make it date
You look fantastic, I didn't recognise you
- What are you doing here? - Avoiding government agents
- Are you here by yourself? - Where'd you get that dress?
It was a birthday present from you, actually
- I have great taste. - Yes
- You, uh, wanna dance? - Oh, no, thank you. No
Am I making you uncomfortable?
No, no
I always forget to wear a deodorant
and dance with my boss in front of everyone
that I work with, in a dress with no back
- You look great, you smell great. - Oh, God
But I could fire you, if that'd take the edge off
I actually don't think that you could tie your shoes without me
- I'd make it a week
Really? What's your social security number?
- Five. - Five?
You're missing just a couple of digits there
The other eight? That's why I got you, for the other eight
- How about a little air? - Yes, I need some air
- That was totally weird. - Totally harmless
It was totally not harmless, by the way
- Nobody was watching us. - Everybody who I work with...
I think you lost objectivity. I think they... we just danced
No, it was not just the dance!
You don't understand because you're you
And everybody knows exactly who you are, and how you are with girls
And all that, which is completely fine...
But you know, then me, you're my boss and I'm dancing...
Because it makes me look like... the one who's trying to...
I just think you're overstating, that's all
And we're here, and then I'm... wearing this ridiculous dress...
And then we were dancing like that and...
- I would like a drink, please. - Got it
I would like a vodka martini, please
Very dry with olives, lot of olives
like at least three olives
Two vodka martinis, extra dry, extra olives, extra fast
Make one of them dirty
- Well... Tony Stark! - Oh, hey!
Fancy seeing you here
- Carrie. - Christine. - That's right
You have a lot of nerve showing up here tonight
Can I at least get a reaction from you?
Panic. I would say panic is my reaction
I was referring to your company's involvement
in this latest atrocity. - They just put my name
on the invitation, I don't know what to tell you
I actually almost bought it, hook, line and sinker
I was out of town for a couple of months, in case you didn't hear
Is this what you call accountability?
It's a town called Gulmira. Heard of it?
- When were these taken? - Yesterday
- I didn't approve any shipment. - Well, your company did
Well, I'm not my company
- Please, do you mind? - Have you seen these pictures?
- What's going on? - Tony, you can't afford to be this naive
I was naive before, when they said:
Here's the line, we don't cross it, this is how we do business
If we're double-dealing under the table... are we?
Let's take a picture. Come on
Picture time!
Tony... who do you think locked you out?
I was the one who filed the injunction against you
It's the only way I can protect you
The fifteen miles hike to the outskirts of Gulmira
can only be described as a 'descent into Hell'.
Into a modern day heart of darkness.
Simple farmers and herders from peaceful villages
have been driven from their homes
displaced from their lands by warlords,
emboldened by a newfound power.
Villagers have been forced to take shelter
in whatever ways that they can find.
In the ruins of other villages
or here, in the remnants of the old Soviet smelting plant.
Recent violence has been attributed to a group
of foreign fighters, referred to by locals as the Ten Rings.
As you can see, these men are heavily armed and on a mission.
A mission that can prove fatal to anyone who stands in their way.
With no political will or international pressure,
there's very little hope for these refugees.
Around me, a woman begging for news on her husband
who was kidnapped by insurgents.
Either forced to join their militia...
...to anyone who will stop a child's simple question:
"Where are my mother and father?"
There's very little hope for these refugees,
refugees who can only wonder who, if anyone, will help.
Faster!
Women on the trucks! The weapons here!
Abandon houses! Hurry up!
Hold this rebel!
Put him with the others
Father!
What the hell is this?
Kill this bastard!
You are incompetent!
Turn your head!
Father!
He is all yours
AIR BASE EDWARDS, CALIFORNIA
- What the hell was that? - Are we clear to go in there?
No, sir. They were using human shields
We never got the green light
Department of State, they're gonna be all over this
We got a bogey
Is CIA on the line?
I got them on line, they wanna know if it's us
No, that definitely is not us, sir
- It wasn't navy. - Wasn't marines
I need answers! Can I please get eyes on target?
Get me colonel Rhodes
from the Weapons development down here now!
We ran an ID check and crossed reference
with all known databases. We have nothing
Any high-altitude surveillance in the region?
We've got an AWAC and a Global Hawk in the area
So this things just appeared out of nowhere?
How come it didn't show up on the Radar?
It's got a minimum Radar cross-section, sir
- Is it stealth? - No, sir. It's tiny
We think it's an unmanned aerial vehicle
Colonel, what are we dealing with here?
I'm gonna make a call
- Hello? - Tony?
- Who is this? - It's Rhodes
Sorry, hello?
- I said it's Rhodes. - Speak up, please
- What the hell is that noise? - I'm driving with the top down
Yeah, well I need your help right now
It's funny how that works, huh?
Yeah, speaking of funny, we got a weapons depot
that was just blown up a few cliques from where
you've been held captive. - Well, that's a hot spot
Sounds like someone stepped in and did you job for you
Why do you sound out of breath, Tony?
- I was just jogging at the canyon. - I thought you were driving
Right, I was driving to the canyon where I'm gonna jog
Are you sure you don't have any tech in that area...
...I should know about? - Nope
Bogey spotted!
Okay, good, cause I'm staring at one right now
and it's about to be blown to kingdom come
War room, this is Whiplash One. I've got the bogey in my sight
- Whiplash One, what is it? - I've got no idea
- You have radio contact? - Non responsive, sir
Then you are clear to engage
Bogey just went supersonic. I got a lock!
Incoming missile. - Flairs!
Wait a second! Bogey deployed flairs
Deploy flaps!
Holly... this thing just drove off the Radar, sir!
Satellite image has been lost
- No way that's the U.A.V. - What is it?
I can't see anything
Whatever it was, it just bought the farm
I think bogey has been handled, sir
- Hello? - Hi, Rhodey, it's me. - It's who?
I'm sorry, it IS me. You asked what that was, and it was me
No, see.. this isn't a game. You do not send civilian equipment
into my active war zone. You understand that?
It's not a piece of equipment. I am in it. It's a suit. It's me!
Rhodey, you got anything for me?
Mark your position and return to base. - Roger that
On your belly! It looks like a... man!
Shake him off! Move, move!
I'm hit! I'm hit!
Eject! Eject!
Whiplash One down
- Whiplash 2, do you see a chute? - Negative! No chute! No chute!
My chute's jammed!
Sir, I've got a visual on a bogey
Whiplash 2, reengage. If you get a clear shot, you take it!
Major, we don't even know what we're shooting at. Call off the Raptors
That thing just took out an F-22 inside the legal no-fly zone
Whiplash 2, if you have a clear shot, take it
They've been reengaged. Execute evasive maneuver
Keep going!
Got a chute! Got a chute!
- Tony, are you still there? - Hey, thanks
Oh my God, you crazy son of a bitch!
You owe me a plane, you know that, right?
Yeah, well, technically he hit me, so...
Now are you gonna come by and see what I'm working on? - No, no
The less I know the better
Now what am I supposed to tell to the press?
Training exercise. Isn't that the usual BS?
It's not that simple
An unfortunate training exercise
involving an F-22 Raptor occurred yesterday
I'm pleased to report that the pilot was not injured
As for the unexpected turn of events on the ground in Gulmira
it is still unclear who or what intervened
but I can assure you that the U.S. government was not involved
Oh, it isn't that bad, sir
Sir, the more you struggle, the more this is going to hurt
Be gentle, this is my first time
I designed this to come off
Please try not to move
What's going on here?
Let's face it, this is not the worst thing you've caught me doing
Are those bullet holes?
Welcome
Compliments of Tony Stark
If you killed him when you were supposed to, you'd still have a face
You paid us trinkets to kill a prince
Show me the weapon
Come. Leave your guards outside
His escape bore unexpected fruit
So this is how he did it
This is only a first crude effort. Stark has perfected his design
He has made a masterpiece of death
A man with a dozen of these can rule all of Asia
And you dream of Stark's throne
We have a common enemy
We are still in business
I will give you these designs...
...as a gift
And in return...
...I hope you repay me with a gift of iron soldiers
This is the only gift you will receive
Technology
That's always been your Achilles heel in this part of the world
Don't worry. It will only last for 15 minutes
That's the least of your problems
Bring the armour and the rest of it
Alright, lets finish up here
Set up Sector 16 underneath the Arc reactor
And I want this dead and masked. Recruit our top engineers
I want a prototype right away
Are you busy?
I need you to go to my office and hack into the mainframe
You're gonna retrieve all the recent shipping manifests
This is a lock chip, this will get you in
It's probably under Executive Files, if not...
they put it on a ghost drive, in which case you need to look
for the lowest numeric heading
And what do you plan to do with this information
if I bring it back here? - Same drill
They've been dealing under the table, I'm gonna stop them
I'm gonna find my weapons and destroy them
Tony...
you know that I would help you with anything
but I can not help you if you're gonna start all of this again
There is nothing except this. There's no art openings
there's no benefit, there's nothing to sign
There's the next mission, and nothing else
Is that so?
Well, then I quit
You stood by my side all these years
while I reaped the benefits of destruction
And now that I'm trying to protect the people
that I've put in harm's way, your going to walk out?
You're gonna kill yourself, Tony. I'm not gonna be a part of it
I shouldn't be alive... unless it was for a reason
I'm not crazy, Pepper
I just finally know what I have to do
And I know in my heart that it's right
You're all I have too, you know
Sector 16?
What are you up to, Obadiah?
You did not tell us that the target you paid us to kill
was the great Tony Stark. As you can see
Obadiah Stane, your deception and lies will cost you dearly
The price to kill Tony Stark has just gone up
So... what are we gonna do about this?
I know what you're going through, Pepper
Ah, Tony. He always gets the good stuff, doesn't he?
I was so happy...
when he came home. It was like we got him back from the dead
And now I realise...
...well, Tony never really did come home, did he?
He left a part of himself in that cave
Breaks my heart
Well...
He is a complicated person
He's been through a lot. I think he'll be alright
You are a very rare woman
Tony doesn't know how lucky he is
Thank you. Thanks
I gotta get back there
Is that today's paper?
Yes
- Do you mind? - Not at all
- Puzzle. - Of course
Take care
Ms. Potts? We had an appointment
Did you forget about our appointment?
Nope. Right now, come with me
I'll give you the meeting of your life. Your office
We've been working our best
Absolutely, we're... I'm gonna have to call you back
Mr. Stane? Sir, we've explored what you've asked us
and it seems as though there's a little hiccup, actually...
- A hiccup? - Yes, to power the suit...
sir, the technology actually doesn't exist. So it's...
Wait, wait, the technology?
William, here is the technology
I've asked you to simply make it smaller
Okay, sir, that's what we're trying to do
but honestly, it's impossible
Tony Stark was able to build this in a cave!
With a box of scraps!
I'm sorry. I'm not Tony Stark
Tony?
Tony, are you there?
Breathe
Easy, easy...
You remember this one, right?
It's a shame the government didn't approve
There are so many applications regarding short-term paralysis
Ah, Tony
When I ordered the hit on you
I was worried that I was...
...killing the golden goose
But, you see...
it was just fate that you survived it
leaving one last golden egg to give
You really think that just because you have an idea
it belongs to you?
Your father, he helped to give us the atomic bomb
Now what kind of world would it be today
if he was as selfish as you?
Oh, it's beautiful
Ah, Tony...
This is your Ninth Symphony
What a masterpiece! Look at that
This is your legacy
The generation of weapons...
...with this at its heart
The weapons that will help stir the world back on course
With the balance of power in our hands
In the right hands
I wish you could see my prototype
It's not as... not as conservative as yours
Too bad you had to involve Pepper in this
I would've preferred that she lived
What do you mean he paid to have Tony killed?
Pepper, slow down
Why would Obadiah... okay, where is Tony now?
I don't know, he's not answering his phone
Please go there and make sure everything's okay
Thank you, Rhodey. I know a shortcut
Good boy
Tony?
Tony!
- Are you okay? - Where is Pepper?
She's fine. She's with five agents that are about to arrest Obadiah
That's not gonna be enough
Section 16
Section 16...
There it is
My key's not working, it's not opening the door
Wow, what is that? It's like a little device, like a thing
that's gonna pick the lock? -You may wanna take few steps back
That's the coolest thing I've ever seen. - Not bad, huh?
Let's do it
You need me to do anything else?
Keep the skies clear
Damn!
Next time, baby
Looks like you were right
He was building a suit
I thought it'll be bigger
Take him out!
How do you think the Mark One chest piece is gonna hold up?
48% power and falling, sir
That chest piece was never designed for sustained flight
Keep me posted
- Pepper. - Tony?
- Tony, are you okay? - I'm fine
- Obadiah, he's gone insane. - I know. Listen!
- You better get outta there! - He built the suit
Get outta there, right now!
Where do you think you're going?
Your services are no longer required
Stane!
- I love this suit! - Put them down
Collateral damage, Tony
Defer the power to chest piece
Power reduced to 19%
Lady!
For thirty years, I've been holding you up
I built this company from nothing!
And nothing is gonna stand in my way
And least of all, you
Impressive! You upgraded your armour
I've made some upgrades of my own
Sir, it appears that his suit can fly
Duly noted. Take me to the maximum altitude
With only 15% power, the odds of reaching that altitude...
I know the math! Do it!
Sir, you're not gonna believe this. That thing is back
Get me major Allen. Scramble the jets!
Not necessary, people, just the training exercise
- 13% power, sir. - Climb!
-11%. - Keep going!
- 7% power. - Just leave it on the screen, stop telling me
You had a great idea, Tony
but my suit is more advanced in every way!
How'd you solve the icing problem?
Icing problem?
Might want to look into it
2%
We are now running on emergency backup power
- Potts! - Tony!
Oh my God, are you okay?
I'm almost dead of power, I gotta get out of this thing
I'll be right there. - Nice try
Weapons status?
Repulsors are off line
Flairs!
Very clever, Tony
- Potts. - Tony!
This isn't working, we're gonna have to overload the reactor
and blast the roof. - How are you gonna do that?
You're gonna do it
Go to the central console, open up bolt of circuits
When I clear the roof I'll let you know
and you're gonna hit the master bypass button
That's gonna fry everything up here
Okay, I am going in now
Make sure you wait till I clear the roof, I'll buy you some time
This looks important
I never had a taste for this sort of thing
but I must admit, I'm deeply enjoying the suit
You finally outdid yourself, Tony
It would've made your father proud
It's ready, Tony! Get off the roof!
Tony!
How ironic, Tony!
Trying to free the world of weapons
you gave it the best one ever!
- Pepper! - And now...
I'm gonna kill you with it!
You ripped up my targeting system
- Hit the button! - You told me not to!
Hold still, you little prick
- Just do it! - You'll die!
Push it!
Tony!
We've all received the official statement
of what occurred at Stark Industries last night
There have been unconfirmed reports that a robotic prototype
malfunctioned and caused damage to the Arc reactor
"Iron Man", that's kinda catchy. It's got a nice ring to it
It's not technically accurate, since it's a gold-titanium alloy
but it's kinda attractive name anyway
Here is your alibi
- Okay. - You were on your yacht
We told Pepper to put you in Avalon all night
and sworn statements from 50 of your guests
I was thinking maybe we should say it was just Pepper and me
alone on the island
That's what happened. Just read it word for word
There's nothing about Stane here
That's been handled. He's on vacation
Small aircraft have such a poor safety record
What about this whole story that it's a body guard?
He's my body...? That's kinda flimsy
This isn't my first rodeo, Mr. Stark
Just stick to the official statement and soon this will all be behind you
You've got 90 seconds
Oh, agent Coulson
I just wanted to say thank you very much for all of your help
That's what we do. You'll be hearing from us
- From the Strategic Homeland... - Just call us S.H.I.E.L.D
Right
- Lets get the show on the road. - You know, it's actually...
...not that bad... even I don't think I'm Iron Man
- You're not Iron Man. - Yeah I am
- You're not. - Suite yourself
If I were Iron Man, I'd have this girlfriend
who knew my true identity. She'd be a wreck
She'd always be worrying that I was gonna die
and yet proud of a man I become. She'd be...
wildly conflicted, which would only make her more...
crazy about me. Tell me you never think about that night?
- What night? - You know
Are you talking about... the night that we danced
and went up to the roof...
and then...
you went downstairs to get me a drink, and you...
left me there by myself?
Is that the night you're talking about?
I thought so
- Will that be all, Mr. Stark? - Yes, that'd be all, Ms. Potts
And now Mr. Stark has prepared a statement
He will not be taking any questions, thank you
It's been a while since I was in front of you
I figure I'll stick to the cards this time
There's been speculation that I was involved in the events
that occurred on a freeway and the rooftop...
I'm sorry Mr. Stark, but do you honestly expect us to believe that
that was a bodyguard in a suit, that conveniently appeared
despite the fact that... - I know that it's confusing...
It is one thing to question the official story
and another entirely to make wild accusations
or insinuate that I'm a superhero
- I never said you're a superhero. - You didn't?
Well, good, because that would be outlandish and...
...fantastic
I'm just not the hero type, clearly. With this...
long list of character defects and all the mistakes I've made
largely in public
- Just stick to the cards. - Yeah, okay
The truth is...
I am Iron Man
Jarvis? - Welcome home, sir
You think you're the only Superhero in the world?
We are part a bigger universe, yet we know nothing
Who the hell are you?
Nick Fury, the Director of SHIELD
Oh
I'm here to talk to you about the Avenger Initiative